Yamin Siahmargooei - Software Engineer

• Location: Gorgan, Iran

• Site: https://yamins.ir

ullet Email: yamin[dot]siahmargooei[at]gmail[dot]com

• Phone: +98-933-888-0330

• Telegram: https://t.me/yamins

• LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/yaminsm

• Github: https://github.com/yamin8000

• Stackoverflow: Profile Link

Summary

I'm a Computer Engineer specializing in Software Engineering. Skilled in Android App Development and have professional experience in Kotlin and Java. I also have semi-professional knowledge in C, C++, C#, Python, and PHP programming languages. As a Software Engineer, I'm interested in any type of software development; From Embedded programming utilizing AVR/ATmega with C, IoT projects by making use of Raspberry Pi/Arduino, Back-End projects using Ktor framework, Full-stack projects using Laravel, and mostly Android projects which are my main area of expertise.

Experiences

• Freelance Software Engineer - Self-Employed Sep 2020 - Present

Most of my freelance works is associated with developing Android applications using Kotlin/Java (Compose/Views) and publishing them in Appstores such as F-Droid and CafeBazaar also I published some Android libraries in Maven Repository

• Software Engineer - Aryan Spad Sep 2020 - November 2023, 3 yrs and 3 mos I developed some Android applications for contractors and helped in development of an Email Queue program using Kotlin and Ktor framework and I was also part of small team that helped developing multiple websites using Laravel, .NET Core and Wordpress

• Gap year - Career Break Dec 2018 - Sep 2020, 1 yr 10 mos Mandatory Military Service • IoT Apprentice - Golestan University Dec 2017 - Aug 2018, 9 mos

Worked on a project developing a platform for devices in IoT using Raspberry Pi as a Gateway

• Technical Support Specialist - Xperian.ir Jan 2014 - Feb 2017, 3 yrs 2 mos Technical Support for Wordpress and content creation about Sony Xperia devices

Education

• Golestan University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Engineering Sep 2014 - Sep 2018

Software Engineering

Thesis: Implementation of the server and gateway application based on the client-server model in the framework of a Internet of Things network

Skills

• Programming Languages

- Kotlin Professional
- Java Professional
- SQL Intermediate
- − C# Intermediate
- PHP Basic
- Python Basic
- C Basic
- C++ Basic
- 8086 Assembly Basic
- Rust Basic
- Golang Basic

• Industry Knowledge

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Android Development
- Git
- Data Structures
- Refactoring
- Clean Code
- Regular Expressions
- Internet of Things (IoT)
- Raspberry Pi
- AVR/ATmega

• Tools and Technologies

- Android Studio
- IntelliJ IDEA
- Visual Studio
- SQL Server
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Material Design
- ANTLR
- Laravel
- GitHub/Gitlab

Languages

English - Full professional proficiency,

Persian - Native or bilingual proficiency